JOSEPH J. CRUZ

15921 93rd Ave. E. Puyallup, WA 98375 | 253-888 5514 josephjcruz1724@gmail.com

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY PROFESSIONAL:

Customer service driven I.T. Professional with a background in support of small to large scale environments of users and network devices. Proficient in teaching and communicating with a diverse number of users at various skill levels. Experience in managing a team and using time management to complete projects. With proficiency in hardware replace and repair.

EXPERIENCE:

SEFNCO Communication 1019 39th Ave SE #200 Puyallup, WA 98374

Position: Help Desk Technician

02/18/2020-Present

- Servicing over 1,000 employees and being the first point of contact for support phone calls
- Manage ticket distribution for IT Department using Service Now ticketing system
- AD Manager Plus to manage users and computer accounts
- Clearly communicate technical solutions in a user friendly/non-technical manner
- Work with internal employees via phone, email, Microsoft Teams chat, or remotely to resolve problems
- Perform basic troubleshooting and problem resolution for all types of IT infrastructure as assigned – hardware, software, telecommunications, business application, customer connectivity, LAN, WAN, and others
- Use of Teamviewer to remote into user's pc, phone, and tablets
- Remote into server to set permissions for user to various network shares
- Multifactor authentication support (OKTA Admin)

Allergy and Asthma Specialty Services

07/15/2019-02/14/2020

11203 Bridgeport Way SW Lakewood, WA 98499

Position: System Admin/Support Specialist

- Only point of contact for 30 Employees at 5 locations
- Setup of user accounts using Active Directory
- Setup of Microsoft Exchange mailbox and Office 365 tools that the staff uses
- Assist the medical staff with issues using N-Central remote access
- Manage and monitor proprietary programs that are used for the clinic's medical records, where privacy and security of patient information is a priority
- Hardware repair/replacement on PC's and software installations

- Deployment and setup of thin clients for the medical staff to access the server
- Setup of RDS (remote desktop services) for the Doctor's to work from home on their laptops
- Maintain and manage the printers for all the locations
- Maintain the phone systems that are VOIP, this includes clinic extensions, setup, and greeting system
- Maintain and updating of the company's website
- First point of contact with any third-party venders, this includes any ordering and warranty issues

Larson Automotive Group

02/25/2019-07/12/2019

7815 S Tacoma Way Tacoma, WA 98409 **Position:** IT Specialist

- Service over 500 employees with technical needs, that include setup new user accounts, E-mail service, proprietary programs, and hardware issues
- Network management, software deployment, and various application administration
- Manage VOIP system for all employees, this includes setup and management
- Work with external partners for various hardware and software vendors for the most appropriate system implementation
- Provide training to non-technical employees on the business's information system
- Install and configure computer hardware operating systems and applications
- Use of Freshdesk ticketing system to diagnose and priorities user issues
- Communication between employees through E-mail, face-to-face, and over the phone to resolve issues.

Wrapjax

08/08/2016-02/23/2019

11110 25th Avenue East, Suite B

Tacoma, WA 98445 **Position:** Installer

- Installation of vinyl graphics that are applied to cars, vans, and trucks
- Vehicle are used as a form of advertising or for personal customizing
- The process includes the preparation of the vehicle, and the installation of the graphics using hand tools
- Attention to detail with working on luxury, commercial, and standard vehicles

EDUCATION:

Pierce College Puyallup

Fall 2014-June 2018

- Associates in IT Network Engineer
- Certification in Windows Computer Systems Admin

Course Work: Public Speaking, Technical Writing, Human Relations in the Workplace, Math, and English.

CCNA and Windows: Intro to Networks, Routing and Switches, Windows Client Operating System, Managing Windows Server, Administering Windows Server, Configuring Advance Windows Server,

Computer Operating Systems, Connecting Networks, Intro to programming, Linux, PowerShell, and Computer Installations.

Accomplishments: Placed on Dean's list 3 consecutive quarter for a GPA higher than 3.5 and President's list for a 4.0 GPA for fall 2018 quarter.

INTERNSHIP:

Washington State Fair

Sept 2018

Support the ticket sellers in the maintenance of hardware, software, and other systems. Troubleshoot issues with equipment like printers, computers, and servers. Apply software updates backups when requested. Research unusual bugs or issues the company encounters

Supervisor:

Ryan Gilbertson Network Administrative Services ryan@nasvc.com

Cell: 253-237-4224

Spanaway Lake High School

Spanaway, WA

1999-2001

Diploma